<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
  <section>
    <title>Setting up export</title>
    <para>pt_extlist offers several exporters for lists. You can select from a list of pre-defined export formats or implement your own exporters. Here is a step-by-step explanation on how to set up export:</para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Go to the page on which you have your list set up. </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>You have to include a static template for export settings on the page you want to export list data. Go to the Template module and modify the template of the page. Switch to the &quot;Includes&quot; tab of your template record and select &quot;[pt_extlist] Export settings (pt_extlist)&quot;. Save your template and switch to page module.</para>
        <figure>
          <title>Inclusion of static template for export</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata align="center" fileref="../images/integrators_guide_1_1.jpg" width="450" format="jpg"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Insert a new content element of type &quot;General Plugin&quot;. Select &quot;ExtList&quot; as selected Plugin.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Switch to the &quot;General Options&quot; tab and select list identifier of the list you want to export. Select &quot;Export&quot; as Plugin Type.</para>
        <figure>
          <title>Set plugin type to &quot;Export&quot;</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata align="center" fileref="../images/integrators_guide_1_3.jpg" format="jpg" width="450"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Switch to the &quot;Export Settings&quot; tab and select list identifier of the list you want to export. Select Export Type and Download Type. Hint: If you cannot select an Export Type, you most likely forgot to include static template for export on the page you are currently working. See step 2!</para>
        <figure>
          <title>Configuration for exporting a list as Excel sheet</title>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata align="center" fileref="../images/integrators_guide_1_2.jpg" width="450" format="jpg"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Save your content element and switch to frontend view.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>You will now see a download in your Frontend that enables you to download configured export document with your list data.</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Why are there 2 list identifiers?</emphasis></para>
    <para>Almost everytime you want to export some data from your list, you also want to change the way the list looks like in your export. Therefore you can select a different list identifier for export than for your &quot;normal&quot; list. This way you can configure the changes for the exported list on the same page you have your &quot;normal&quot; list. In previous versions of pt_list, you had to create a special page with special TS-settings for your exported list. By chosing a second identifier for your exported list, this is no longer required!</para>
    <section>
      <title>Requirements for Excel export</title>
      <para>There are special requirements for setting up Excel Export. You have to install the module PHPExcel which is available via a special PEAR channel. In order to install PHPExcel, refer to their website: http://phpexcel.codeplex.com/releases/view/45412</para>
      <para>The current installation process looks like this:</para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Set up PEAR on your system.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Use the following command to make PEAR channel known to your PEAR:<programlisting>pear channel-discover pear.pearplex.net</programlisting></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Use the following command to install PHPExcel on your system:<programlisting>pear install pearplex/PHPExcel</programlisting></para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </section>
  </section>
</section>
