<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><book xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:m="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
  <title>
    <inlinemediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="Images/logo_punktde.png" contentwidth="70" format="png" valign="bottom"/>
      </imageobject>
    </inlinemediaobject>
  </title>
  <title>pt_extlist</title>
  <title>documentation</title>
  <info>
    <legalnotice>
      <para>publisher: punkt.de</para>
      <para>publication: 2010</para>
      <para>print-out: 1</para>
      <para>person responsible: Daniel Lienert, Michael Knoll</para>
      <para>Copyright, brands and trademarks : The author will make every endeavor
  to consider in all publications copyrights of the used illustrations,
  sounds, video sequences and texts, to use illustrations, sounds, video
  sequences produced by himself, or to fall back on license-free
  illustrations, sounds, video sequences and texts. All brands and trade
  marks, mentioned within the internet offer, which may be registered and
  protected by third parties are unrestricted subject to the regulations of
  the respective valid laws and to the rights of the registered owners.
  However, due to the bare mention of an brand or trademark, one can not jump
  to the conclusion, that brand names are not protected by rights of third
  parties! The copyright for published objects, produced by the author
  himself, remains only with the author of the pages. A duplication or a use
  of such illustrations, sounds, video sequences and texts in other electronic
  or printed publications without the strict agreement of the author is not
  permitted.</para>
      <para>disclaimer: The author does not take over any guarantee for the
  topicality, the correctness, completeness or quality of the information,
  made available. Liability claims against the author, concerning damage of
  idealistic or of material kind, which was caused by the use or not use of
  the presented information and/or by the use of incorrect and incomplete
  information, are in principle impossible, so far as not a deliberate or
  roughly negligent fault can be proved on the part of the author. The
  documents and graphics on this Web site can be affected by technical
  inaccuracies or misprints, for which we don&apos;t assume any liability. punkt.de any
  time and without announcement can carry out technical amendments or
  improvements at the products which don&apos;t have to be documented absolutely on
  this Web site. Therefore punkt.de doesn&apos;t take any guarantee for the correctness
  of the details on this Web site. A legally binding contract on no account
  takes place alone by the information given here. Please consult us before
  you make use of the information given here for your application. The author
  expressly reserves itself the right, to change, to supplement or to delete
  parts of the pages or the entire offer or occasionally or finally to stop
  the publication without separate announcement.</para>
    </legalnotice>
  </info>
  <preface>
    <title>Reading this </title>
    <table>
      <title>Information about the document</title>
      <tgroup cols="2">
        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry>author</entry>
            <entry>Michael Knoll, Daniel Lienert</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>version</entry>
            <entry>1.0</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>status</entry>
            <entry>draft</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>confidentiality</entry>
            <entry>internal </entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>document type</entry>
            <entry>extension documentation </entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>start</entry>
            <entry>
              <para>18.10.2010</para>
            </entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>last date of editing</entry>
            <entry>
              <para><?dbtimestamp format="d.m.Y"?></para>
            </entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>file name</entry>
            <entry>
              <para><!-- ###DOCUMENT_NAME_WITH_PDF_SUFFIX### --> </para>
            </entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>
    <para>A documentation for users, administrators and developers.</para>
    <para>The users will learn how to install and setup a demo list. The
  administrators will learn setting up a list and plugin configuration. The
  developers will learn what pt_extlist is about and how they can manipulate
  pt_extlist.</para>
    <para>The users and administrators need the basic knowledge about
  programming. </para>
  </preface>
  <chapter>
    <title>TypoScript Reference (TSRef)</title>
    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="Sections/TypoScriptReference.xml"/>
  </chapter>
    <!-- We do not need an appendix yet
  <chapter>
    <title>Appendix</title>
    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="Sections/Glossary.xml" encoding="UTF-8"/>
   </chapter>
   -->
</book>
